<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Ramblings of a Hybrid Web Developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://jrodsmitty.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jrodsmitty.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-06T08:30:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jrodsmitty.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jarrod Smith]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sitecore Fix: Partially-cut-off 'Add to Here' Button in Page Editor]]></title>
    <link href="http://jrodsmitty.github.io/blog/2014/11/05/sitecore-fix-for-partially-cut-off-add-to-here-button-in-page-editor/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-05T22:40:39-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jrodsmitty.github.io/blog/2014/11/05/sitecore-fix-for-partially-cut-off-add-to-here-button-in-page-editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since we first installed Sitecore 7.2 rev. 140228 (first release), we have noticed an odd visual bug in Page Editor.  We have since uninstall/reinstalled to be at the latest release: 7.2 rev. 140526.  However, we still see the issue. There appears to be a small rectangular &ldquo;knock-out&rdquo; overlaying the bottom edge of the &ldquo;Add to here&rdquo; button.  I was able to track it down to the &ldquo;webedit.css&rdquo; file in the root /Website folder where Sitecore is installed.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://jrodsmitty.github.io/images/add-here-bug.png" title="[100%] [auto] [Page Editor Bug [Page Editor Bug]]" ></p>

<p>In the webedit.css file, line 604, I changed &ldquo;height: 11px;&rdquo; to &ldquo;height: 24px;&rdquo; and that fixed the issue.  The complete modified class looks like:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>.scInsertionHandleCenter
</span><span class='line'>{
</span><span class='line'>    background: transparent url('/sitecore/shell/themes/standard/images/pageeditor/move_to_here_center.png') repeat-x;
</span><span class='line'>    float: left;
</span><span class='line'>    height: 24px;
</span><span class='line'>    padding-top: 3px;
</span><span class='line'>    padding-bottom: 9px;
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><img src="http://jrodsmitty.github.io/images/add-here-bug-fixed.png" title="[100%] [auto] [Page Editor Bug Fix [Page Editor Bug Fix]]" ></p>

<p>I had first emailed Sitecore support about this bug, but they replied saying they weren&rsquo;t able to reproduce the issue with a clean install of 7.2. I find that kind of odd, since I have also noticed the bug during a demo of Sitecore 8 at the Milwaukee Sitecore Meetup group. The presenter was demoing the Experience Editor (previously Page Editor), and lo and behold, there it was!</p>

<p>So it&rsquo;s obviously an issue that exists, although I&rsquo;m not sure what release(s) it&rsquo;s getting introduced in.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blog Manifesto]]></title>
    <link href="http://jrodsmitty.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/blog-manifesto/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T22:31:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jrodsmitty.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/blog-manifesto</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On many occasions over the last nine years I have found myself facing all flavors of weird browser quirks, software quirks, and many other head-bashing frustrations. Had I had the forethought to document all the solutions to my problems as they occurred, I might already have helped many others outside my immediate dev team avoid the same frustrations I/we had.</p>

<p>My hope for this blog is that I do just that - share my frustrations, learnings, and solutions to all sorts of problems I face on a daily basis, with practical, working examples that you can actually use to solve your problems.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Per my experience and interests, I&rsquo;d categorize myself as a hybrid (Front-End / Back-End) developer. I have worked at a number of digital marketing agencies over the years, working with a wide variety of tools, and have gained some training/certifications along the way too (both a Kentico and Sitecore certified developer). My latest escapades bring me to C#.NET MVC (w/ Razor, of course!) and Sitecore CMS. Many of my posts will focus on Sitecore development, but I plan to branch off from time to time to venture into other topics as well.</p>

<p>I hope you find some useful nuggets in my blog. Happy coding!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
